Blaise Irakoze

Address: Kigali, Rwanda Phone: +250788211579

Email: <u>blaiseirakoze50@gmail.com</u>

Github: https://github.com/blaiseirakoze

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/blaise-irakoze-2124a812b

Summary

I am an experienced software engineer. I have the skills necessary to design, develop, and maintain high-quality software applications. With a strong background in Software engineering and programming languages such as Java, Javascript and C++. I am able to analyze complex problems and create elegant solutions that meet the needs of clients.

I have experience working on a variety of projects, from small-scale applications to large-scale enterprise systems. I am comfortable working with both front-end and back-end technologies, and I am well-versed in modern software development methodologies such as Agile and DevOps.

Experience

AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT

Qtsoftwareltd, **Kigali** - *Software Developer*

- Analysis.
- Full Stack web development.

JULY 2020 - AUGUST 2021

Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc, Kigali - Software Developer

- Inhouse solutions development.
- Monitor, analyze and report performance statistics for internal systems.
- Developing new internal and external entities.

MAY 2019 - AUGUST 2019

MINECOFIN(IFMIS), Kigali - Intern

- Learned technologies such as spring framework, hibernate, ZK, maven, SVN, web services, unit and integration test.
- I have had an opportunity to Join the team in the analysis of umurenge sacco system.
- Workshop where i build a simple web application to apply the skills i learned

Education

SEPTEMBER 2015 - NOVEMBER 2020

Adventist University Of Central Africa, Kigali - Ao

I hold a bachelor degree of information technology focused in software engineering.

Skills



Recent projects

APRIL 2022 - ONGOING

Smart admin system - QTsoftwareltd

This is a web application includes the following modules: (Certificate of completion Certificate)

- E Approval
- Task management
- Meeting and minutes management
- Bulletin board and post notification management
- E Folder

MAY 2022 - JULY 2022

E-Tender - QTsoftwareltd

• This is a platform designed to give access to tenders' full information on time to a company suppliers and vendors.

JANUARY 2021 - MARCH 2022

E-correspondence - QTsoftwareltd

 This is a portal where banks, insurances and others access BNR services. (Certificate of completion <u>Certificate</u>)

FEBRUARY 2022 - APRIL 2022

OCF App(Online Collect Funds) - Groupeya ltd

• This is a mobile application used to send funds to someone in need. It's integrated with MTN so that the funds go directly to MOMO(MTN Mobile Money) of the fund.

DECEMBER 2020 - APRIL 2021

Digital archive - Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc

• This is a GTBank inhouse portal used to manage and store clients account files and all other related files.

JULY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020

MTN Real time liquidation - Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc

• This is a GTBank integration with a tele-communication organization(MTN) used by their vendors who use GTBank accounts to initiate and receive their payments in real time.

JUNE 2019 - MAY 2020

ECMS(Electronic claim management system) - E-baza

 This is a system that is involved in car maintenance and brought the gap to the study on how to recover losses in companies and break the corruption system in vehicle maintenance. https://umuhuza.rw/

Certificates

Employment certificate - Guaranty Trust Bank(Rwanda) Plc

- This is a certificate given by GTBank to employee
- Skills: Banking system and software development

Certificate

React frontend to back - udemy

- This is the certificate of compilation.
- Skills: Reactjs, React router, Axios, Redux

Certificate

Cloud DevOps Engineer - Udacity Nanodegree Project

- This program includes projects that teach how to create continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) pipelines, deploy massive infrastructure securely using code, and operationalize microservices using Kubernetes.

Certificate

E-Correspondence project - QT Global Software Ltd

- Certificate of completion **Certificate**

Smart admin system project - QT Global Software Ltd

- Certificate of completion Certificate

Languages

English - Fluent

Kinyarwanda - *Native*

French - Basic

Interests

Fullstack web development	DevOps	Mobile application development	
System architecture and design		Data science	Microservices
Enterprise application			

Blaise Irakoze.